Leena Lallmon

Summary

I'm a Software Engineer based in Montreal, Canada who enjoys problem solving. I am the co-creator of Fjord (fjord-framework.github.io ②), an open source framework that provides a real-time API Proxy for Apache Kafka. I have multiple years of experience in the Ruby and JavaScript ecosystems, and I am comfortable with Golang, AWS and Docker.

Professional Experience

Co-creator & Software Engineer, Fjord

2021 - present

- Collaborated on the prototype of the API Server and Kafka Consumer process using Node.js, KafkaJS and MongoDB
- Isolated and containerized Fjord components using Docker for deployment to AWS cloud infrastructure
- Assembled a multi-broker, distributed Kafka cluster with security (firewall, SASL-PLAIN)
- Contributed to AWS ECS Clusters for the SSE servers and Kafka consumer groups using Fargate launch type, Elasticache for Redis as a publishsubscribe mechanism between the Kafka consumer groups and the SSE servers
- Load tested to handle over 8500 concurrent connections
- Utilized a CLI tool that deploys all of Fjord's AWS components based on user's requirements
- Co-authored a comprehensive technical case study ☑ documenting design decisions

Full-Stack Web Developer, Self-Employed

2020 - 2021

Developed open-source software, some highlighted projects include:

- Ruby Blogger, a Ruby library command line developer tool to track exceptions
- Contact Manager, a JavaScript, Express, Bulma CRUD app with a Node API server
- Spry, a Kanban style Trello clone built with MongoDB, Express, React, Redux and axios

Social Worker, Various Employers

2011 - 2019

- Work in food security, mental health and austism
- Founding member of ADAMA (Association de développement des arts martiaux adaptés)

Skills

Backend

- Node.js
- ExpressRuby
- COL
- SQL
- RESTful APIs
- Webhooks
- SSE

Frontend

- JavaScript (ES6)
- React
- Redux
- HTML
- EventSource API

ToolingGit

- Github
- Docker
- Linux

Cloud

- AWS EC2
- AWS ECS
- AWS Fargate
- AWS Elasticache for Redis
- AWS VPC
- AWS ALB
- GCP VM
- Digital Ocean Droplet

Education

2020 - 2021

Multi-year full-stack Software Engineering curriculum with mastery-based learning